According to YouTube statistics, only a
small percentage of people that watch my
videos are actually subscribed. So if
you end up liking this video, consider
subscribing. It's free and you can
always un I got a call from Sacha Baron
Cohen one night.
And he says, "Hey, I don't know if you
know my characters." But I said, "Oh
yeah, I said, 'Listen, Borat.'" I said,
"I almost pissed myself laughing." It's
still the funniest movie I've ever seen
in my life. So he said, "Well, I've got
this character Bruno." I said, "Yeah,
yeah, the the gay Austrian fashion
correspondent."
>> [music]
>> He said, "Yeah." So he made me sign a
non-disclosure agreement. And um he
said, "Literally nobody's in on the gag
except um Pam Anderson.
Literally no one else in the film was in
on the gag. Well, except
uh
>> [music]
>> that was in Borat, except Borat's
assistant. So anyway, um he said, "We
can't let anybody know that it's me and
that I'm in character." And I said,
"Okay, so what can I do for you?" And he
said,
"We're going to go to the Middle East.
I want to get in front of bonafide
terrorists," [music] he said. I'm
thinking Hezbollah or Al-Qaeda. And I
want to show them Polaroids of men
having
like hardcore
And I want to ask them if [music] this
is a form of torture and should these
men be sent to Guantanamo?
>> Oh [__] god. [laughter]
So I said,
I go, "Oh."
That's a that's a bad idea.
Yeah, and I said, "You know, just as a
general rule, you really shouldn't mess
with the religious types." I go,
"They'll kill you, they'll kill your
crew, they'll go out onto the street and
kill people who remind them of you."
You know, I I generally never talk to
people on airplanes. I I listen to music
or I read a book or a magazine or
something. I just don't say anything. I
was flying from Milan to Eastern Europe
one time and there was this Italian guy
next to me [music] who just would not
shut his mouth.
And he kept asking me, "What do you do
for a living? What do you do for a
living?" And
>> [music]
>> you know, I said, "Well,
I'm involved in
the import-export business." Oh, what do
you import? What do you export? I said,
"Ah, whatever whatever, you know, turns
things into money."
He [music] just wouldn't stop.
And finally, I said, "Look,
I smuggle women and cigarettes from
Eastern Europe, okay? Are you happy
now?" And he goes,
"I don't think I approve." [music]
I said, "I didn't ask for your [__]
approval."
And then he just kind of sat there with
his head down the rest of the time.
[music]
And it's it's not like it is in the
James Bond movies, where everybody's
like, "Wow, right on top of their game."
No, they're a lot of dopes. I I was just
telling a friend of mine yesterday, um
we were getting ready to go on a
the honest-to-god truth, we're already
getting ready to go on a raid in in
Pakistan. We're going to raid an
Al-Qaeda safe house. And I remember
saying, "Where's Where's Chris?"
Oh, uh Chris couldn't come. I said,
"What do you mean he couldn't come?
Well, that's why he's here." No, it
turned out Chris beat his wife. So, uh
we
>> have this rule, if you get caught
beating your wife, you can't carry a
gun.
So, he can't go on the raid without a
gun. I said, "Okay, where's Jimmy?" Now,
Jimmy got psycho backed. Psychologically
evacuated. I said, "Why?" He went nuts
this morning.
I was like, "All right, all right, let's
just let's just go with what we have."
So, it's not like What are you doing
there?
He goes,
"I've been killing people. What do you
think I've been doing?"
And it dawned on me that that's why they
hadn't sent me.
Because I kept saying,
>> [music]
>> "You need linguists to do the
interrogations."
You want to do interrogations?
They're just shooting people.
So,
I finally went into the Deputy Director
of the Counterterrorism Center's office.
He was
>> [music]
>> an old friend of mine. And I said, "If
If you don't send me to Afghanistan
right now, I said, as God is my witness,
I'm walking straight to Exxon with my
Arabic, and I am not looking back." He's
like, "Will you relax?"
He goes, "All right, all right." And
then he says to me like this,
"You are
Jewish?"
And I said, "I am not recruitable. Don't
even think about trying to recruit me."
I said, "My name is John Kiryakou. I was
overt, not undercover. So, I said, 'My
name is John Kiryakou and I'm going to
brief you on Saddam Hussein's
psychology.'"
And the Shin Bet guy, he has his glasses
like this and he says,
"Spell your name?"
So, I spell it, which made me angry.
And then he says to me like this,
"You are
Jewish?"
And I said, "I am not recruitable.
Don't even think about trying to recruit
me."
I was enraged. Mhm.
So, afterwards,
everybody was laughing
and they said, "They've done that to all
of us.
Every one of us. They tried to tell
Right to your face, right in front of
everybody, they try to recruit you. I
got back to the office. He said, my boss
said, "How did it go?" And I said, "I'm
so mad right now." And he said, "Mossad
tried to recruit you, didn't they?"
And I said, "Yes." He said, "They do
that to everybody.
They're just crude about it. Just like a
punch in the face."
Yeah, this this is one of these
incidents that leads to PTSD.
Um
when I my family and I first arrived in
Athens, uh the embassy put us up in a in
an apartment uh because they hadn't yet
gotten a house. I I went sort of out of
cycle.
Most people go summer
to summer and I arrived a couple of
months in.
So, uh they needed to go out and find a
house.
So, we're in this apartment and then
they finally find us a house and um
and we're moving all our stuff up to the
house. Uh
the the embassy has a truck for most of
our boxes and then my wife was in a car
and I was in my armored car.
And I had just bought a TV at the PX. It
It was a big one. It took up the whole
backseat. Not big like we have today,
but you know, it was 25 years ago.
So, it was pretty big. It took up the
whole seat.
So, I'm driving up the same Kifissias
Avenue.
And there's a
there's a motorcyclist and he's trying
really hard to stay in my
blind spot.
And I thought, that's kind of odd. So, I
speed up and he speeds up. I slow down,
he slows down.
I move over a lane, he moves over lane.
My wife calls me. She's in the car ahead
of me and she says, "Do you see this
guy?" And I said, "Yeah, I'm starting to
get nervous."
And she said, "You don't think it's 17
November?" And I said, "They can't
possibly be on me yet."
I said, "I don't know I don't know what
this guy is doing."
And she said, "Are you nervous?" I said,
"Yeah, nervous enough that I think I'm
going to hit him.
I'm going to I'm going to try to hit
him."
And she said, "Okay." So, I hung up and
I sped up and he sped up and then I
slammed my brakes as hard as I could and
I swerved right to hit him. And I barely
missed him.
So,
we did this a couple of times.
And then there's this
enormous intersection. How do you
control people who don't actually
[music] work for you? You can't.
And you risk them going rogue, which of
course they do because it's their
nature.
If you're being If you're being
contracted to run an assassination
[music] program,
you're going to go out there and
assassinate people.
Well, everybody's [music] human and you
make mistakes.
And you convince yourself that, you
know, Ahmed Schmamed is [music] a really
bad guy.
And actually, Nah, it's a cousin with a
similar name, but you just put a bullet
in this guy's head. Nah, okay. Yeah,
you're right. Just write [music] a check
for 100 grand to his widow and just move
on.
And that's not cool. It's a It's a
crime. You can't just go around [music]
murdering people because you think they
might be a bad guy.
And so Panetta, I never really liked
Panetta. Just cuz he's not a nice guy.
But um [music] but Panetta was right to
shut that down.
Okay, so um [music]
What are the What are the legalities
then of a
Blackwater team going out to hit [music]
somebody as if a ground branch team
would. It's Is it like I think title 10
title 50? Right. One's military, one's
CIA. I can't remember. I good-looking
go-getter.
And he's [music] like
I was targeting this woman and she has
access to the [music] prime minister to
Syria, but she's no longer a target.
You're going to have to find somebody
else.
He ended up [music] marrying her.
Wow.
>> Yeah. He What do you think of the new
Chinese mega embassy opening in London?
Do you think it's a threat to the UK?
Yes, I do. I've been following this
issue. The Chinese tried the same thing
in Washington and we said nothing doing.
So they're kind of split up. They have
They have a large-ish embassy
on a street of embassies. They're
directly across the street from the
Israelis. They're down the street from
like the Vietnamese and the Qataris and
you know, people like that.
But um their housing is in a different
place just off Embassy Row in the
Kalorama neighborhood of uh of
Washington. They're sort of split up.
The trade mission's in a different
building.
In London, they are planning this
ginormous embassy. It would be the
biggest embassy in the world.
And it takes the entire city block in
London. There've been protests in the
streets about this embassy.
And for whatever reason
Keir Starmer said, "Now what I I don't
really care what the British people
want. Sure, you can have your embassy."
Well, this is going to be you know, talk
about the United States used to be
accused a lot of of having
a spy den in their embassy. This is
going to be the mother of all spy dens.
Yeah, without a doubt. And mark my
words, this is not a one-and-done. The
Chinese are going to seek to build
embassies like this all over the world.
God knows they have the money for it.
>> [music]
[music]